Preliminary Inventory to the On Davis Papers on Squatters' Rights TAM.365
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
On Davis Papers on Squatters' Rights
circa 1980s - 1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Davis, On
TAM.365
1.25 Linear Feet In one record carton, 2 folders in oversize shared boxes, and one flat file folder
This collection consists of materials created by a group of squatters at 537 East 13th St in the 1980s. They were collected by On Davis, an activist involved in the squatters' rights movement.
Conditions Governing Access
Materias are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
On Davis sent a gift of his papers on squatters' rights in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.021.
Biographical Note
On Davis was involved in the 1980s squatters' rights movement in New York City's East Village which culminated in the Tompkins Square Park Police Riot of August 1988.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of subject files, clippings, oversized artwork, account books and a diary composed by squatters at 537 East 13th Street.
Tompkins Square Park Riot, New York, N.Y., 1988.; Graphic arts; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions.; Posters.; Works of art.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Squatters -- New York (State) -- New York
- 209 East 7th Street: House Meetings, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 209 East 7th Street: Legal Documents, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 327-329 East 8th Street, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 537 East 13th Street: Homesteaders, Fire Reports, Invoices, Organizational Meeting Notes, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 537 East 13th Street Homesteaders: Notebooks, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 537 East 13th Street: Receipt, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Adverse Possession, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Clippings and Articles Related to Housings, Squatters, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Community Board No. 3 Manhattan, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Community Land Trust, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Department of Housing Preservation and Development, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "East Villager", 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fliers, leaflet, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Free Mumia Abu-Jamal, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Haiti Anti-Intervention Committee, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Handwritten Notes, Outlines, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Hevesi-Campaign Finance Reports, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Homelessness, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Homesteaders, Squatters, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Inventories of Repair, Jobs, and House Goods: 537 East 13th Street Apt. 2F, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lower East Side Drug Free Zone, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_b3a0d3c8267e231c521fb42e21e916b6)
- Lower East Side Housing and Evictions, Related Documents (Includes Lower Est Side Anti-Displacement Project, Village Independent Democrats, Action Team of the Lower East Side), 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Lower East Side Housing Publications, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Neighborhood Anti-Crime Center, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 24)
- New York State and City Law Enforcement, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Notebooks, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "Piss Bucket", 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "The Shadows", 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Tompkins Square Park, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Newspapers, 1980s-2000s (Box Shared Tamiment 175, Folder 2, Box Shared Tamiment 171, Folder 5)
- Posters, 1980s-2000s (Box Shared Tamiment 175, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 18 Right)